Let's drill the Basic Double Twist.
Shall we?
So let's start with our Single, so think about the right hip going forward and then back, forward, and now keep all the weight on the right foot.
Forward, back, then switch left foot, back.
Forward, back; forward, back.
Good.
Five, six, double time.
And forward, back; forward, back; forward, back; forward; right foot, left foot; right foot, left foot.
Notice the right hip is keeping time, alright.
Hands stay in place, they're not flying all around, good.
Feet are facing straight ahead, belly button's pulled in, chest is lifted.
Try this in front of a mirror and make sure you're doing the body positions correctly.
Good.
Left hip, forward, back; forward, back, forward, back, forward, double time.
And forward, back; forward, back; forward, back; forward; forward, back; forward, back.
Slow it down.
And forward, back; forward, back; forward, back and double time.
Forward, back; forward, back; left foot, right foot; left foot, right foot; left hip's keeping time now, hands aren't moving.
Keep the belly button pulled in, chest lifted.
Good.
Slow it down one more time.
And forward, back; forward, back; forward, back.
Very nice.